More than 10 billion people.
100多亿人口，
Over 7,000 languages spoken.
7000多种语言，
90 million songs, 42 billion fruit trees,
9千万首歌谣，420亿颗果树，
900 zettabytes of data,
900泽字节信息，
90 million beehives,
9千万个蜂窝，
six million dentists,
6百万名牙医，
142 million square kilometers of protected park
1.42亿平方千米保护公园
and one city.
——尽在一个城市。
(Ambient music)
（氛围音乐）
A Planet City.
一个地球城。
What I've just described is my thought experiment
我所描述的是我
for this world called Planet City,
名为“星球城市”世界的思想实验，
an imaginary city for 10 billion people.
星球城市是拥有百亿人口的想象之城，
The projected global population of the world in 2050.
容纳2050年世界人口预测数量。
I design environments for the film and television industry,
我在电影和电视行业中设计环境，
and I believe that by creating imaginary worlds,
相信我们通过打造想象世界，
we can connect emotionally to the ideas and challenges of our future.
能对未来的想法和挑战 产生情绪上的共鸣。
So we've been creating Planet City
所以我们在创造星球城市，
in response to the rising red line on the graph of climate change
以应对气候变化图上不断上升的红线。
because world building and storytelling
因为除了形象化数据，
can do so much more than just visualize this data.
创建世界和讲故事的作用还有很多，
They can help us to dramatize data.
这能帮我们在影片中展现数据。
So in speculative cities,
在推测的城市里，
we can immerse ourselves in the various consequences
我们能沉浸式地体验如今的抉择
of the decisions we face today.
所带来的不同后果。
They can be both cautionary tales or road maps to an aspirational future.
它们既可以是警示性的故事， 也可以是通往理想未来的线路图。
So I invite you all to join me as we journey along the canals of Planet City.
让我邀请你们所有人， 沿着地球城运河，一同参观。
If we listen, we can hear the hum and crackle
闪烁的蓝红LED灯 照亮了城市下游的农田，
of flickering blue and red LEDs
侧耳聆听，会察觉到
as they illuminate the lower reaches of the city's farm fields.
它们发出的嗡嗡声和噼啪声。
It smells of soil and hard drives
城里混杂着土壤、硬盘
and sweet fruit.
和甜果的气味。
A purple sunrise over a new kind of wild.
新样的野生环境带来紫色的日出。
So five years ago, seminal biologist Edward O. Wilson
5年前，伟大的生物学家 爱德华·威尔森（Edward O. Wilson）
proposed a new world he called Half-Earth,
提出了名为“半个地球”的新世界，
a plan to stave off mass extinction by devoting half the surface of the earth
这个计划旨在把一半地球表面 全然献给大自然，
completely to nature
留下的另一半用于
and then consolidating human development to the other half that would remain.
巩固人类发展，以避免大规模灭绝。
And this is where the speculation of Planet City began.
这便是星球城市推测的源头。
And as we started to visualize and design
随着我们开始形象化并设计
this radical reversal of our planetary sprawl,
地球无序扩张所造成的剧变，
we soon realized we could actually go much further.
我们很快意识到还能再进一步。
In its most provocative form,
最理想的情况下，
at the intensity of the densest city that already exists,
星球城市能以目前最密集城市的状态
Planet City could occupy as little as 0.02 percent earth.
可以只占0.02%的地表。
Could we imagine coming to such a global consensus,
我们能想象达成这样的全球共识，
radically reversing all of our existing assumptions?
从根本上扭转我们现有的全部假设吗？
What would it take?
要怎样打造星球城市？
What would it look like?
它长什么样？
(Ambient music)
（氛围音乐）
So our Planet City would allow us to surrender
我们的星球城市几乎将
almost the entirety of the globe to nature,
整个地球归还于自然，
to return stolen lands and rewild in our wake.
放手人类盗取的土地， 让其回归自然原态。
A new national park of the world to be visited and tended,
星球城市就像打造并照料 全新的国家公园，
not engineered for extraction.
仅供参观，绝不开采。
The invisible lines that once divided us would fade beneath this planet of trees.
无形将我们分离的界线 将因树丛消失。
In the streets of Planet City
在星球城市的街道，
we can prototype some of the necessary lifestyle changes that might be required
我们可以模拟出一些 生活方式必要改变的原型，
in order for us to sustain human life.
这些改变旨在延续人类生命。
We can explore how such a new world could evolve,
我们可以探索新世界会如何进化，
not in a singular forced move,
但不是被迫一次性完成变化，
but perhaps in a slow, multigenerational retreat from the world we once knew.
而是可能要几代人缓慢地退出 我们已知的世界。
To build Planet City, we could remine our old cities rather than virgin ground.
我们能在旧城的基础上建造地球城， 不必开采处女地。
No new resources would need to be consumed or extracted to build this city.
打造这座城无需消费开采新的资源。
The world's shipping fleet that currently scatters matter ripped from the earth
如今世界上的航运船队 将商品洒落至商场和店面，
into our malls and storefronts
那些消费品是在地球身上扯下的。
could be reversed
这种情况能被扭转，
and repurposed to bring all this material back together again
只重新利用、重聚所有材料
into the geological strata of our new city.
到我们新城市的地质层中。
The ghosts of nation states would give way to new neighborhoods
演绎新的关怀、归属感与再创造力，
that could be formed around shared cultural practices
民族国家的幽灵就将让位给新的邻里，
as we perform new myths of care, belonging and recreation.
这些邻里可以围绕 共同的文化实践形成。
(Ambient music)
（氛围音乐）
If we were to map all the world's celebrations onto a calendar,
如果全世界的庆典都纳入一个日历，
then we'd realize that running through Planet City
那在星球城市里奔跑
would be this continuous festival procession
就会一直身处庆祝节日的队伍中，
dancing across a 365 day loop, each day amongst the flickering confetti.
在亮晶晶的五彩纸屑中舞动， 365天每天如此循环。
It would intersect with the new carnival culture,
这样一来， 人们能无限循环体验新颜色、
endlessly cycling through new colors, costumes and cacophonies.
新服饰和喧闹声，认识新的节日文化。
And to design the systems of Planet City,
为了设计星球城市的系统，
we travelled to and filmed
我们去到当今世界现有的
all of the megascaled renewable energy and agriculture sites
所有大型新能源场和农场，
that currently exist around the world today:
并将其拍摄下来。
the world's largest solar farm in the Mojave Desert,
其中包括莫哈维沙漠里 世界上最大的太阳能发电站、
the illuminated indoor farms protecting crops from harsh Siberian winters,
保护农作物免受西伯利亚 严冬影响的室内照明农场、
the most productive wind energy network in Gansu, China,
中国贵州最高效的风力发电网，
the world's largest algae farm in Western Australia.
以及澳大利亚西部 世界上最大的藻类农场。
These monumental infrastructures
这些巨型基础设施
are evidence that much of the technologies required
都证明了绝大部分
to support the generation of our climate
支撑气候产物所需的技术
are actually already here.
已然问世。
And in Planet City, we just remove the political roadblocks
地球城消除目前阻碍发展的
or the lack of cultural investment that's currently holding them back
政治障碍或文化投资不足的问题。
and we visualize them operating at these global scales,
我们预想这些情形 在这些全球范围内发生，
but not forgotten out on an industrial periphery,
但这不会被遗忘在工业外围，
but woven through the very fabric and life of the city itself.
而是交织在城市本身的结构和生活中。
So before dawn breaks in Planet City,
地球城日落前，
thousands of autonomous cleaning blades squeak along the solar fields.
数以千计的自动清洁刀片 在太阳能发电场上吱吱作响。
Waves of mirrors will ripple to rotate to chase the changing light.
镜子的波浪会起伏旋转， 追逐变化的光线。
A billion panels collected from all over the world.
10亿块太阳能电池板 从世界各地收集而来。
And the batteries of Planet City will be alive with fish and pink algae,
鱼和粉色海藻将为星球城市功能，
as excess wind and solar power
额外的风能和太阳能
will be used to pump water through the canals
会把水从运河里
to high-altitude holding lakes in the city's upper floors.
抽到城市高层的高海拔湖泊中。
Power will be stored here as potential energy
电力不存于资源密集型的锂电池，
rather than resource-intensive lithium batteries.
而是作为势能储存于此。
And tides rise and fall as the lights glow and turbines spin.
随着灯光的闪耀和涡轮机的旋转， 潮汐也随之起伏。
So although wildly provocative,
因此，尽管极其诱人，
imaginary worlds can be grounded
想象中的世界可以立足于
in the real science and technology of the present moment,
如今真实的科技，
meaning we can project ourselves into these futures.
这意味着我们可以 将自己投射到这种未来。
What would it be like to live here, to fish amongst the city battery lakes,
在这里生活会是什么样子呢？ 或许会在城市的电池湖中钓鱼，
to follow the seasons up through the towers,
在塔楼上追随季节，
collecting honey with the Planet City beekeepers,
和星球城市的养蜂人一起采蜜，
to fall in love amongst the pink algae blooms before harvest?
于收获季之前的粉红海藻中恋爱。
So Planet City is not a proposal.
所以尽管星球城市并非是提案，
However, it's a provocation.
它十分动人。
It's a thought experiment that shows us
这个思想实验告诉我们
we don't need to tread so hard across the Earth
无需在地球上如此艰难地跋涉，
because if we can get these systems working at the scale of 10 billion,
因为如果能够让这些系统 容纳下100亿人，
then the only things stopping us
阻止我们
rethinking and consolidating our existing cities is ourselves,
重新思考和巩固现有城市的 唯一因素就是我们自己，
our own politics and prejudices, biases and blind spots.
我们自己的政治观点和偏见盲区。
So in many ways,
所以在许多方面而言，
all of us have been living in a planetary-scaled city all along.
所有人一直在行星规模的城市里生活。
We have urbanized our planet
我们已经城市化了我们的地球，
from the scale of the cell to the tectonic plate.
小到细胞规模，到大到地壳版块。
Planet City is both entirely fictional,
星球城市既是全然虚构的，
but also already here.
又已然存在。
Simultaneously, a challenging image of a possible tomorrow
同时，星球城市是对可能发生的未来的 一种富有挑战的形象，
and an urgent illumination of the environmental questions
也是我们如今所面临环境问题的
that are facing us today.
一种急需的照亮。
So at the end of our journey,
我们刚刚在星球城市
as we've been wandering through this sci-fi safari through Planet City,
徘徊于科幻的野生动物园。 旅程结束之际，
we will return to where we first started to look back on our own cities again,
让我们回到起始点， 用新的眼光再次回顾
but with new eyes.
我们自己的城市。
This journey has been a call to actively visualize our possible futures.
这段旅程在呼吁我们积极想象 我们可能面临的未来——
Imaginary worlds in which we can collectively shape
我们共同塑造的，
where we all might want to go next.
想生活于此的想象世界。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。